Okay guys welcome to another video, in this video we will explore the honey pod, already
we have seen the IPS ideas as well as the firewall, the working mechanism and how it will
protect the network from the protectors, so now we will discuss another security mechanism
that was commonly used in organizations, so the name was a honey pod, so the name looks
like a beard, it is a honey with a pod, it is a cyber security mechanism designed to attract
detect anomalies, the malicious activity by simulating a vulnerable system or a network,
okay, so basically let me explain with the diagram, so let us think of it, here is
your router and it is your router and here is a application server or any service which
is very needle for an organization, but it was a public facing, it will be available
in internet, so anyone if they have authorized username and password, anyone from any home,
they can use their internet and they can use their internet and they can access this
service, okay, so in that organization there is a honey pod as been implemented, okay, so let
us think of it here is a attacker, so he is used to attack the web servers, so it is a web
server, this hobby is to attack a web server, but what is this honey pod, this honey pod
is like a already we have seen, it is a mechanism designed to attract the hackers, okay,
so the detector will think this is a real server, but this is a fake server designed to
attract the hackers, okay, it is designed to attract the hackers, so they think of it,
this is the real server and they will try to enter into the machine, but they are unable
to access into the machine, but they will connect to the honey pod, so it will act
like a real web server and the attacker things, yeah I hacked the organizations, I hacked
the web server, but that was not a real scenario, but because attacker hacked the fake
honey pod server, so that's why it is used to attract the hackers, okay, it will be
a vulnerable system, okay, so attacker tried attacker will come into the organization
through any vulnerability, and what we will do, we will do the attack analysis, how he
enter into the machine, which vulnerability he used and which is the compromise to password,
username and password, he will use and we will check for the vulnerability, discover which
vulnerability he tried to get to the machine, and we will improve our security team to the
incident response, so we all know there is an incident response team in every server security
company, so we can implement a good incident response, a team we can learn from this attack,
so basically if there is a threat attacker, first of all we will learn from the threat
attacker, so how he is entering into the machine, and what techniques he will use, and
we will get all the IOCs, the indicator of compromise like IP address, and which command
line he used, all this, all the activities we will observe from the threat attacker, and
then we will design a rule to detect that automatically by our next-gen antivirus tools,
okay, so if there is an IP address, the attacker used, we will block that IP address in
the antivirus software, or a firewall, so the next time if the attacker tried to login
into the machine by using that IP, the antivirus software or the firewall or EDR, it will
automatically block that IP, okay, so it is a legal evidence how the attacker entered
into the machine, so because the honey pod save all the logs, what are the things, what
are the stuff the attacker did in the target machine, in the fake machine, so he it logs
every, every each and everything, so we have a legal evidence of attacker, how he entered
into the machine, and what are the commands he executed, so what is the IOC standalone, okay,
so basically it will attract the hackers to hack into the machine, so by that we can
as a security analyst, we can do our investigation, and we can improve our incident response
team or any threat tunnelist team, inside the organization, okay, it is a very interesting
field, the threat tunnelist, these things and all we will do some foreign stuff, and we can
do an incident response, we can implement a new detection tools to stop the threat next
time, yep, so this is the diagram where the honey pod will be placed, it will be placed
after the, after the router, the first and it will be placed in a service network with
the, it's the application service and our web service and the honey pod will be placed
after the external firewall, so first honey pod was placed before the firewall, the next
honey pod was placed after the firewall, so if the attacker things, it is a real web server
and he will try to attack the machine and a threat, a threat tunnelist or a, a, a foreign
six tunnelist, we can do some investigation and you can find out how the attacker can enter into
the machine, okay, so this is the over our explanation of honey pod and let me see the another
security mechanism that was broadly used in every organization, so this is the, one of
the entry point of most of the threat actors, the ransomware, especially the ransomware threat
actor, they will use VPNs to get into their organizations, they will use the VPN vulnerabilities
to enter into the organization, okay, so let us see what's VPN, so it's a, it's a visual
private network that allows user to create a secure and encrypted connection over a less secure
network, such as internet, okay, so let me see some diagrams about the VPN, so you are
for an example, so you are in an airport, so this is the airport and you have connected
with the airport network through the Wi-Fi and your machine is here, so also the, one of
the threat actor, the attacker connected in the Wi-Fi network, so he can able to see the
data what you are sending, okay, he can able to sniff all the data, what you are sending,
what, from the request and response, so what the request sending from your, your host
machine and what's the response received from the other servers, okay, he can able to see
everything, so we will do, we have a mechanism like a VPN visual private network, so basically
we know what's encryption, so VPN supports the encryption, so VPN will create an encrypted
channel, so it will create an encrypted channel, so attacker, if the attacker was here,
if he tries to sniff all the data, he was monitoring all the data from these two machines,
he was unable to understand what we are sending, okay, so the first thing in VPN, it
has an encryption, so we are using for our security, you know, unsecured networks, so
basically this is the first point, such as the internet and the less secure network, okay,
so also we are using in our home network also because if we need a security, let's
think of very big organizations and they don't know if any of the machines get compromised,
so if there's a VPN has been implemented, so they can able to securely transfer their data
and receive their data, right, so next thing the privacy, so VPN basically hide your IP address,
so no one able to track, or track you, so where you are and who you are, this details
will be hidden, so VPN will support a privacy for you and there's something, so when you
are connecting to any internet it will be, it will be change your IP address basically,
I will give you a real example of how it will do, so security in the sense it will encrypt
all the network traffic and wife in it, which is more vulnerable to attack, so bypassing
geo restriction, so for example if your country, so for my country, India will sometime
block some, some of the websites, right, so if we are implementing the VPN, so we can bypass
this restriction, so because it will change the IP address to other location, okay, so
we can by easily bypass the geo location restrictions, this will be a good thing, so another
one of the important, very important things we need to notice, there is a remote access,
so in COVID time in 2020 to 2022, so everyone are in home, you are working in a home,
so if everyone will be in the remote network, right, so let's think of it, here is a home,
so you are working in a home, and here is your organization, here is your router, and
the organization have a VPN, so it will be in the network, so you can, you need to access
some web servers inside of our organization, so you are a network administrator or so we
serve administrator, so you can able to use the VPN for a secure and safe communication, it will
be encrypted, right, so you can use the VPN to get into the web servers, and you can configure
what you want, okay, this is the real thing, so what you used, what you used to do during
your COVID time, so when you are in the web from home, so it will be in the safe and secure
channel, but the attackers, the hackers will use the VPN vulnerability, so if you have compromised
the VPN, so you can easily enter into the web server, okay, so I will show that publicly,
so if we search of the 48 VPN, show down, so you can easily go to show down and you can
notice everything, so here is, I just checked the 48, and you can see the 48 VPN was asking
your username and password to me, basically 48 was a VPN provider, so here you can see
they have a separate VPN, they are a VPN providers, so the VPN will be in both, the hardware
as well as the software we can see there, from here the VPN will be looked like this,
okay, so it will support encryption and all, so if you have the username and password,
you can login into the organization and you can hack whatever you want, okay, so there
will be a lot of CV for a VPN, so the attackers will use this CV and get into the machines,
so it will be one of the easy things, because it was publicly faced, we will take, this
is a public facing application, we can able to access it from our internal, so this VPN
is public facing, if we have a username and password, we can able to login into that machine,
so you can see a critical vulnerability was found in the VPN and SSL function, and there's
a lot of vulnerabilities like remote code execution, send all remote code execution, so
CV 2024, 21762, it has a remote code execution, you can execute any remote code in any of
the parameter and you can get into the machines, like you can execute the I/F_con suite
command, like that and you can access whatever you want, like the vulnerabilities like
that, okay, so RLS, you can post your malicious code in new web server and you can give
the URLs, like we can, we will see all the things in upcoming topics and we can discuss
whatever you want, so let us think of it, this is our remote server and you are hosting
a server dot exefil, so this will execute in the VPN and it will give you the reverse
connection to you, so the vulnerabilities are like that, so you can easily get into the
machines, okay, so it's a remote access software, you have a, if you have a username and
post it, you can easily access it remotely, okay, the VPN will be hosted like this and
there's internet and there's VPN gateway, so it will be hosted like this, so if you have
the credentials or if the VPN have any vulnerability, you can easily enter into any of
the machines inside the organizations, so the ransomware protectors mostly use, so 48 VPNs
and others is go or any VPNs to spread their ransomware across the environment, okay,
so ransomware update of exploiting 48 networks, ransomware hackers is hijacked 48 VPNs,
okay, so not only the 48 VPN, not a lot of VPN, so every VPN source vulnerable on of the
time, so after that they will release a patch for that, so there we can fix, so let me see
what's about VPN, so I have a bit different VPN, so now you can see my IP address was 1172027.125,
if I give you my IP here, it will be showing some other IPs, okay, so my IP will be 15
and our 192 on 246.32, let's put this in virus total, let's understand what this virus
total, saying it's showing my IP was a malware and it's the media, let's connect it to the VPN,
and now I am in Singapore, let it will load, let's give me some seconds, let it will be
loaded, once it gets loaded we will refresh that, so now you can see my IP was changed to 146.70.149.104,
so if I put this in virus total, so now it's a VPN IP and it's from Singapore, so the virus
total showing, it also VPN IP, so the VPN is basically changed your IP address to your location,
so if any of the IP websites has been blocked in India, so we can access that websites through the
VPNs, okay, so not only that you can easily switch from one place to another, so by using the
location tab, so here we have all the locations, so you have switch all the locations, what locations
you want, so I'm not using the premium version, so it's 250 free for, if you want to upgrade,
you can go ahead and upgrade, I'm not interested, I'm not using VPN for my day-to-day activities,
I don't need that, so this is the overall explanation of the virtual private network, so let's
understand, it's more vulnerable and you can easily enter into the organization through the VPN
networks, if you do need to, if you need to research something about the vulnerability, just go ahead
and research about the vulnerability, because most of the threat factors, especially the ransomware
threat factors, they will use VPN networks to get into the organizations and spread their
ransomware binaries across the network, okay, many of them are of freshers while taking this course,
but don't worry about the big big words like ransomware, VPNs, and the organizations, etc, etc,
so we will learn in the upcoming top sections, on by one, okay, so thank you guys, I hope you
have a clear understanding, understanding about the funny part of the VPN, we will continue the
discussion in the next video, see you, bye bye.